# Babafemi Adojutelegan

106, Victoria Street, Ojota +2349065195264 • phemmylekan@gmail.com

# **Professional Summary**

An Energetic Software Developer with years of work experience in fast-paced Technology firms. I have excellent development skills with a track record of achieving exceptional results in Software Developments for high-volume businesses. An enthusiastic team player, deep creative thinker and a pragmatic problem solver.

### **Technical Skills**

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Angular
- Vue.js
- Node.js
- Ionic
- Express.js
- GraphQl
- MongoDB
- C#
- PHP

# **Work Experience**

#### **Eminent Software (Nigeria)**

Role - Software Developer

Jan 2019 - Present

- Translate business requirements into technical specifications and implementations.
- Develop, maintain and release web related user interfaces and prepare systems design documentation by applying company, industry and governmental standards.
- Create, develop and maintain systems designs by preparing design layouts, modifying existing designs and assisting in identifying design discrepancies using design tools.
- Perform user experience activities on projects as necessary.
- Demonstrate technical leadership ability in the Front-end and communication with RESTful web services.
- Perform code reviews and collaborate with peer designers / developers on project work.
- Proven ability to work across multiple functional teams in the creation of an application development and support process.
- Identify and interact with Business Relationship Management and Project Management Office to ensure their needs are being met by the project design.
- Familiar with code management, defect management, ticket and project

management tools.

- Experienced using open source JavaScript libraries.
- Demonstrated ability to solve complex issues.
- Ability to interact professionally with customers and vendors.
- Actively collaborated with a team spread across multiple countries with Azure Dev, Axosoft and JIRA.
- Managed repositories using Azure Dev, Bitbucket and GitHub.
- Implemented Agile/Scrum programming methodologies and continuous integration.
- Performed automated deployments on Azure Dev.
- Environment: Angular, VueJs, NodeJs, ExpressJs, MongoDB, GraphQL, JavaScript, TypeScript, SharePoint SPfx, HTML, CSS, SCSS, git

#### **Helping Hands Home Care (UK)**

March 2017 - September 2017

Role - Web Developer

- Developed dynamic and responsive web application.
- Experienced in Web Designing using Technologies and other web components like HTML, CSS, and WordPress etc.
- Improved the animation, drop down menus and moving images of the website's.
- Exceptional abilities in using source code analysis tools automated build process and unit testing
- Worked hand in hand with team members to expand web activities.
- Managed repositories using GitHub.
- Environment: HTML5, CSS3, Wordpress, JavaScript, Bootstrap, git

#### Accra institute Of Technology (Ghana)

May 2016 - December 2016

Role - Web Developer intern

- Developed applications using Object Oriented PHP.
- Developed Customized views using Wordpress.
- Reduced search time by over 40% by optimizing indexes in the MySQL database.
- Made the front end responsive by incorporating Bootstrap.
- Developed Contact Fill Application using Wordpress and installation and integration of the Application
- online..
- Environment: PHP, HTML, CSS, Wordpress, JavaScript, Bootstrap

#### **Ondo State Ministry Of Finance (Nigeria)**

Jan 2012 - Dec 2013

Role - Web Developer

- Experienced in Web Designing using Technologies and other web components like HTML, CSS, and WordPress etc.
- Modified the existing website applications with user-friendly applications.
- Analyzed images and decided what applications best suit them to create more effective apps.
- Tested the navigation features of the Web Site.
- Improved the animation, drop down menus and moving images of the website.
- Conducted quality assurance testing on web applications.
- Environment: HTML, CSS, WordPress, Photoshop

# **Personal Projects**

### **Recipe App (Front end)**

Recipe App(Back End)

https://github.com/phemmyadot/phissy-recipes-frontend-ionic

Node Js, Express Js, Mongo DB, GraphQL

https://github.com/phemmyadot/phissy-recipe-nodejs--mongodb-backend

Inventory App Vue Js, SCSS, Vuex

https://github.com/phemmyadot/inventory-app

Recipe App (static UI)

Angular

Ionic 4

https://github.com/phemmyadot/phissy-frontend-angular

**Share Point SPFx Webparts** 

React, angular

https://github.com/phemmyadot/SPFx-Webparts

**Roster App (Front End & Back End)** 

Front end- Angular, backend - C#

https://github.com/phemmyadot/RosterApp

# **Major Projects/Collaborations**

ExxonMobil's Trade Captures System ExxonMobil's AI Portal Oceaneering's Media Vault'(OMV) ExxonMobil's LNG/He ENGIE's Connect ENGIE's Public Smart Institutions

## **Education**

### **Bachelor's Degree In Information Technology**

Accra Institute of Technology

### **Introduction To Java Programming**

**Triton College Online** 

### References

http://linkedin.com/in/babafemi-adojutelegan

https://github.com/phemmyadot